你好黑客
hello hackers
欢迎回到pwn学院动态分配器误用模块
welcome to the next video in the Dynamic Allocator Misuse's module of pwn College
我是Yan，我们将讨论Tcache
I'm Yan and we'll be talking about Tcache
什么是Tcache ?
what is Tcache
Tcache是线程本地缓存的缩写
Tcache is short for thread local caching
这是一个ptmalloc特性
it is a ptmalloc feature
是最近几年创建的
created in the last couple of years
还在不断发展
and constantly evolving
这让教学变得很有挑战性
which makes it actually challenging to teach about
这加速了重复申请小的
that speeds up repeated small
小于等于一内存页大小的
and we're talking about things that roughly a page in size or less
在单个线程中的内存分配
allocations in a single thread
现代处理器都是多核的
modern processors are heavily multi core
越来越多的应用程序支持多线程
applications are becoming more and more threaded
所以分配器的线程性能非常重要
and so thread performance for an allocator is very important now
Tcache在ptmalloc中处于这样的位置
Tcache is positioned in such a way in ptmalloc that
你主要通过它与malloc交互
it will be the primary malloc functionality that you will be interacting with
它可能是最重要的部分
this is probably the most important part
至少在挑战问题中
at least to approach the challenge problems
还有在一般探索分配器安全的过程中
and in your exploration of allocator security in general
那么Tcache是如何工作的呢
all right so how does Tcache work
Tcache是用单链表实现的
well Tcache is implemented as a singly linked list
我们将快速看一下这个单链表
we're going to go through a quick recap what a singly linked list is
每个线程对于不同大小的内存块都有对应的链表
each thread has a list header for different sized allocations
基本上是这样的
basically what happens is
在每个线程中都有一个
in each thread there's one instance of this
Tcache_perthread_struct
这就是为什么它名字中有perthread_struct
that's why it's called per thread struct
在结构体中有一个tcache_entry指针数组entries
and in the struct there is a array of Tcache entry pointers
每个指针都指向一个tcache_entry单链表
each of which point to the beginning of a list of Tcache entries
这些单链表装着之前释放的内存
of allocations that were previously freed
它们可以非常快速地被复用
and can be very quickly reused
这些内存
and these allocations
这些单链表被称为bin
these different lists are called bins
不同的bin装不同大小的内存
they are all lists of an allocation of a certain size
堆分配倾向于
heap allocations tend to
在分配时四舍五入到最接近的某个大小
round to the nearest some amount of size when they're allocated
所以你…在这个分配中……
and so you ... in this allocation ...
让我理一下思路
let me click my thoughts
不同大小的内存块放到不同的列表
different sized allocations going to different lists
让我们看一下示意图
let's take a look at this graphically
看看这个链表是如何工作的
take a look at how this linked list works
这是 entry 数组
so here is the entry array
我将演示这些内存块是如何被再次选中的
and I'll determine exactly how these allocations are selected again
原则是
but the bottom line is
在tcache_perthread_struct的前几个entry
the first couple of entries in the Tcache per thread struct
entry 0放16字节内存块
entry 0 is 16 byte allocations
所以如果调用malloc 16（就从entry 0 中取内存块）
so if you malloc 16
entry 1是malloc 32。entry 2是malloc 48，以此类推
entry 1 is malloc 32. entry 2 is malloc 48 and so on
以16字节递增
incrementing in 16
好吧
all right
有一个tcache_perthread_struct实例
there is one copy of a struct
我们就叫它Ben
we're going to call it Ben here
这样就可以用名字指代它
so that we can refer to it by name and
并且Tcache列表中的每个entry
each entry in the Tcache list
额，这是一个指针数组
so this is a pointer array in which
数组元素是Tcache entry 列表的头节点指针
the element is the head of a list of Tcache entries
所以这里的tcache_entry都是先前分配的内存块
so each of these entries is actually the allocation itself
当你释放它时
when you free it
它原来放数据的位置被重用来保存这些指针
its data is reused to hold these pointers
有两个指针，一个指向列表中下一个内存块
so two pointers are going to be a pointer to the next allocation in that list
还有一个指向Ben
and a pointer to the original structure Ben here
我们来看看这是怎么建立起来的
let's see how this is set up
好，想象一下这个场景
all right imagine this scenario right
我会解释左边的代码是如何变成右边的这个图的
and I'll explain how this scenario gets to this view that we had previously
我要把视频关掉一秒钟来提一件事
I'm going to turn off my video for one second to mention one thing
在这里，我们malloc出了这些东西
over here we malloc a bunch of these guys right
当我们释放它们，最终
these all end up when we free them
它们会被添加到缓存中以供以后使用
end up getting added to the cache for later we use
如果我们申请了但不释放
when we malloc stuff and don't free it
就和tcache没有任何关系了
there's nothing to do with the cache
你只是在某处有一块内存
you're just hanging out somewhere in memory
你必须free些东西
until you free something
否则tcache不会被用到
Tcache doesn't come into play
好吧
all right
我把视频打开继续
let's get my video back and roll on
如何变成这样的呢？
alright how did we get here
让我们从分配完这些内存开始
let's start from the end of this the allocation part
这里我们分配了一大堆数据区域
here we allocated a whole bunch of of data regions
我们在这里分配了a b c d e和f
we allocated a b c d e and f here
它们的大小各不相同
they all are of different sizes
现在我们要开始释放他们了
right and now we're about to start freeing them
现在，还没有东西被释放
so right now when nothing is freed
当所有缓存都是空的
when everything you know the cache is empty
所有的计数都是0
we have all of the counts at zero
以及所有的entry都指向NULL
and all of the entries at null
然后我们释放 b
then we free b
释放 b 时会发生什么呢
so what happens when we free b
我们增加计数，然后把它放入缓存
we increment the count we put it in the cache
所以现在有一个16字节的东西
so now there's one thing one 16 byte
b 是一个16字节的内存块
b was a 16 byte allocation
缓存中的一个16字节entry
one 16 byte entry in the cache
所以我们把16字节元素计数设为1
so we put the 16 byte element of count to 1
然后
and then
这个 entry 指针指向B
this entry pointer we point to B
表示这是第一个（释放的）分配
says hey there's that first allocation
然后我们释放a
but then we free a
当我们释放A时会发生什么
right what happens when we free A
计数变成了2
well the count becomes two
现在在 Tcache 中有两个16字节的内存块
now there are two 16 byte allocations in the Tcache
我们把指针指向了a
we changed the pointer to a
然后把a的next指针指向B
and then we change the next pointer of a to B
b的next指针是Null
right the next pointer of b is null
因为B之后什么都没有
because there is nothing after B
它是第一个被放到缓存的
it was the first thing to get put in the cache
它们都有这个 key 指针
and all of them have this key pointer which
我也不知道为什么他们叫 key
actually I don't know why they call the key
但他们都指向tcache_perthread_struct
but it points back to the Tcache per thread struct
他们就是这样判断
that is how they can tell
当前在哪个缓存中
which cache this is currently in
我们马上会讲到为什么ptmalloc需要知道这个
and we'll talk about why they need to why ptmalloc needs to know that in a second
然后我们把列表头更新为a
all right and then we update the head of the list to a
所以现在perthread结构体对应的列表头
so now the head of the list from the perthread struct
指向a
this points to a
然后a指向b
and then a points to B
这是一个单链表
that is a singly linked list
有一个前向指针
there's one forward pointer
在双链表中则会有b指向a
In a double linked list would also have b pointing back to a
相反，这是一个单链表
instead this is a singly linked list
然后它们都指向perthread结构体
and then they all point to the perthread struct
好的，当我们要释放 F 时会发生什么
alright what happened when we gonna be free F
F有点不同，因为F有32字节长
F is a little different because F was 32 bytes long
所以当它释放f
so when it free f
我们最终使用了不同的entry
we end up using a different entry
32字节的entry
the 32 byte entry
基本上
right basically
我们计算entry下标的方法是
the way we compute the entry is
只要把大小除以16
just divide the size by 16
这是第一个，这是第二个，对吧
so this is the first one this is the second one right
第二个entry
second entry
这和我们放入b是一样的
same thing as when we put b in there
它是32字节中唯一的，所以next是Null
it's the only thing so the next is null
key是Ben
the key is ben
32的计数置为1
the count for 32 is 1
32的指针是F
and the pointer for the 32 is F
好的
cool
然后我们释放E
alright then we free E
同样的事情发生了，计数现在是2
same thing happens so the count is now 2
E现在是链表的表头
E is now at the head of the list
E指向F
E points to F
当我们释放C
when we free C
计数就到了3
now the count is 3
这些都是32字节的内存块
these are all 32 byte allocations
列表的头指向最近释放的内存块c
the head of the list points to c that was the most recently freed thing
它被放在头部的原因是
and the reason that it get put in the head is
这对内存的修改最小
that is the few amount of memory operations
只要修改这个和这个
all you have to do is update this and update this
其他一切都保持不变，这很好
everything else stays the same which is very nice
然后 entry 指向C
so and then the entry points to C
C指向E
C points to E
E指向F
E points to F
F指向Null
F points to null
他们都用key指向Ben
and they all point back to Ben
那个tcache_perthread_struct结构体
to the Tcache per threadstruct with their key
最后，当我们释放d的时候
all right and then finally when we free d
D是一个48字节的分配
d is a 48 byte allocation
它被放进自己的bin里
and it goes into its own bucket its own bin
现在bin里只有一个内存块，然后
and there's now one thing in that bin and then
entry指向d, d指向空
the head points to d and d points to null
当我们释放所有这些
as we free all of these
注意那些没有被释放的没有设置key变量
note the ones that aren't freed don't have the key variable set
我是说他们的key可能，额
I mean they probably are the key yeah
它们key变量的位置可能有一些数据
remember they probably have some data in here
这可能是各种数据
this is whatever data
这就是malloc的返回结果（用来放用户的数据）
this is literally the malloc result
好的，让我们在代码中深入研究一下
right let's dive into this actually in code
当free的时候会发生什么
what happens when you free well
首先看释放内存块的大小
first you look at the size of that allocation
我们将在以后的视频中讨论
we'll talk in a future video about
这些内存块是如何，额
how these allocations are
如何跟踪记录内存块大小的
how the size is tracked
然后我们算出entries下标
and we figure out the index by
没错，就是减去1，然后除以16
yeah that's right subtracting 1 and then divided by 16
如果内存块大小是从1到16
so if you have from 1 to 16
就是下标0
that is slot 0
从17到32,下标1，以此类推
from 17 to 32 slot 1 and so forth
然后我们检查
then we check
确保这块内存没有被释放过
make sure that we haven't already been freed
这实际上是一个相当复杂的检查
this is actually a fairly complex check
但原则是
but the bottom line is
简单的说就是
the simple version is
它先检查一下key指针
it starts out with checking that key pointer
这个qword
we're saying is our that first this is a qword
这是第一个8个字节
the first 8 bytes
这是内存块的第二个8字节
the second 8 bytes of the allocation
我们取第二个8字节
we take those second 8 bytes
我们检查它是否等于结构体的地址
and we check does that equal the address of our struct
检查它是否指向ben
are we pointing back to ben
即线程的tcache_perthread_struct结构实例
the Tcache per thread struct instance for our thread
如果不是，如果它发现我们已经释放了这块内存
if not if it finds that we've already freed this
程序会挂掉
the whole program dies
这个安全问题和被破坏了的金丝雀一样
it's the same security problem as a broken canary right
都是严重的问题
means something is going horribly wrong
否则，将被释放内存插入到链表（头插）
otherwise we push the free allocation to the front of the list
我们观察
and we observe that
这是它的代码
here's the code for it
基本上就是取当前头部的地址
we basically take the address of the current head of the struct
然后把它放到（被释放内存的）第一个qword里
and we put that into our first qword
就是它的next指针里
into this next pointer
然后把被释放内存的地址放进
and then we put our address into the entries
perthread_struct对应的entry中
into that list entry in the per thread struct
然后我们增加计数
and then we increment the count
非常简单
super simple and then
我把视频消掉，这样就能看到完整代码
let me vanish my video so you can see this whole line
然后把结构体的地址
and then we record the address of the struct
放到被释放内存的key中
associated with the freed allocation
就是我们的ben
this is our ben that
以后就是检查它
this is what's later checked
来确保我们没有双重释放
to make sure we haven't double freed
好的，正如你再次看到的
right and as you see again
在我们释放d之前，key是空的
when we free before we free d this key was null
在我们释放d之后，这个key的值变成了Ben
after we free d this key the value became ben
好吧
all right
或者说是tcache_perthread_struct的地址
or the address of our Tcache per thread struct
这就是free的原理
so that's how you free
那如何分配内存块呢？基本就是反过来
how do you allocate it's basically that in reverse
在分配时，我们计算大小
on allocation we compute the size
malloc 一个请求大小
you do malloc a requested size
我们计算entries下标
we calculate the index
或者说我们根据请求的大小计算entries下标
rather we compute the index based on that requested size
就和free时一样
the same way we computer in the free
我们检查
we check
这显然是伪代码
this is pseudocode obviously
实际上也如此，会检查tcache_perthread_struct
but we check to see if our Tcache perthread struct
这个线程的缓存
the cache of that specific thread
是否有合适的之前释放的内存块
has anything in its cache
就看那个索引的bin的元素计数是否大于零
if the count of that index of that bin is greater than zero
如果小于等于0，创建一个新的内存块
if not by the way we create a new allocation
我们将在以后的视频中讨论如何创建新的内存块
we'll talk about how that is done in a future video
但如果计数不为零
but if the count is non zero
如果有合适的内存块
if there is something in the allocation
那我们就重用bin的第一个内存块
then we reuse that allocation at the front of the list
基本上我们就是取出entry值
basically we pull out the entry the front of the list
我们把
and we put the
我们用链表中的下一个 tcache_entry 更新 entry指针
we update that entry field with the next entry in the list
好的
right
我们直接取出第一个元素
we just pull out the first entry
这同样也是因为只有很少的内存操作
and that's again very few memory operations
然后减少计数，就可以了
and then we decrement the count and we're good to go
你会注意到有些事情没有做
you'll notice some things that are not done
不会清除链表中的指针
we don't clear out sensitive pointer
所以在malloc的返回结果中还保留了next指针
so that next pointer is still going to be present in the returned allocation
但出于一些奇怪的原因
but for some weird reason
是有清除一些指针
there is some thought to cleaning out pointers
但仅限key指针
only that key pointer
当我们
when we
我会在幻灯片上展示给你们看
I'll show you at run time on the slide
只有key指针被清零
but only the key pointer is zeroed out
我们还
and then the other amazing thing that we don't do is
不检查原来头节点的next指针是否
check if the next pointer
是有意义的
if it makes sense
所以当我们
so when we
当我们分配某些东西时
when we allocate something
我会展示给你看
I'll show you
不确保
we don't check to make sure that
用来更新entry 的东西
what we are updating our entries with
实际上是否有意义
actually makes any sense
好吧
all right
所以
so
让我们看看会发生什么
let's see what happens
我们有这个Tcache结构
we have this Tcache configuration
通过之前的讲解我们知道是如何发展到现在这个样子
we know how we arrived at it from before
在现在这个局面申请内存会发生什么呢
what happens when we start allocating from this now
如果malloc 16会返回a
so if you malloc 16 that will return a
它会检查这个计数
it looks on this count right
它说好的
it it it says okay
这个bin中有两个长度在1到16字节之间的内存块
there are two entries in this bin for things between 1 and 16 bytes
它获取这个a
and it grabs that a
把它返回
it returns it
然后它把这个next放到这里
and then it takes this and moves in in here
哦，让我暂停一下
oops let me pause that
因为我忘记更新幻灯片了
because I forgot to update the slides
等一下
one second
好的，很抱歉
alright sorry about that
你看到的是当我们执行malloc时 a
okay so what you see is when we do the malloc a
我们malloc，传入16，它发现计数不为0
we malloc, 16 it takes, it sees that the count is non 0
它将原来这里的值返回
it returns what used to be here
以前是a。它会把a返回
there used to be a. it returns it
它把a中的next指针写入
and it writes the value of the next pointer in a
写入perthread结构中的相关entry 中
and writes it to b uhh to the relevant entry in the per thread struct
状态是这样的
and the state is this
它递减计数
and it decrements count
然后如果我们分配更多的东西
and then if we then allocate a couple more things
分配的C和E
allocated C and E
或者说分配2次32字节的内存，它会做同样的事
or allocated 2 32 2 times then it does the same thing
首先递减这个，然后
first it it decremented this and then
把E写在这里
wrote E into here
它指向E，然后返回C
and then it it grabbed E and and return C
在第二次分配时，它做同样的事情，返回E
then it did the same thing and it returned E for the second allocation
然后把 F 写在这里
and then it wrote F into here
F 也就是 E 中的next值
what was value of the next pointer in E
你在分配的时候会看到
you'll see as you're allocating
Tcache实现将这个Ben中的指针清空了
the Tcache implementation is nulling out this Ben pointer
但由于某种原因，它没有把这些next指针清零
but it is not nulling out these next pointers for some reason
它也没有做任何检查
it's also not doing any checks
如果不是b
if instead of b
这是一个随机的地址，它很高兴地把它放在这里
this was some random address that had happily put it here
这对你们的作业很重要
that's going to be important for your homework
好吧
all right
当然
and of course
这句话的意思是，下次你malloc的时候
the implication of that is the next time you malloced
你最终会返回那个随机地址
you would end up returning that random address
如果我们再做几次分配
if we do a couple more allocations
d b和F
d b and F you know
我们会把它也从列表中pop出去，这个操作叫"pop"
we'll pop, it's called pop, that from the list as well
最后得到的都是0和
and then we'll end up with all zeros and
还有一堆元素是空的
and a bunch of nulls in the entries right
这些空并不重要
these nulls don't actually matter
据我所知，在现代实现中，这些计数才是最重要的
as far as I can tell the modern implementation  these counts are what matters
如果计数为零
if the counts are zero
只是根本不使用这些值
just won't use these values at all
好吧
alright
如果对空缓存进行malloc怎么办
what if you malloc of an empty cache
它会创建一个新的映射，就像我之前提到的
well it'll create a new mapping like I mentioned before
我们将在以后的视频中讨论这是如何发生的
we'll talk about how that happens in a future video
好吧
alright
那么重点是什么呢
so what is the point here
我想让你们明白的有两点
the reason I wanted you to understand all of this is two things
一个是重复释放
one of them is a double free
让我告诉你会发生什么
so let me show you what happens
当我们释放一个已经释放的分配时
when we free an already freed allocation
过去是这样的
so it used to be
it used to be
你可以用Tcache来做这个
that you could just do this with Tcache
使用Ubuntu 1804中的Tcache版本
with the version of Tcache that's in Ubuntu 1804
就是我们上次课上使用的Tcache版本
the version of Tcache we used last time in class
你可以释放，然后再释放
you could just free and then free again
那时的分配库会执行两次释放
and it would happily go for it
没有安全检查
had no security checks
这是最快的
it was as fast as humanly possible
现在如果你试着这么做，结果是这样的
and now what happened if you try to do that is this
与栈检查失败相同
same as Stack Check fail
它会检测
it'll detect that your
你已经释放了它，然后它会失败
you had already freed this and it'll fail
它是如何检测的
how does it detect it
正如我之前提到的
well as I mentioned a little while back
它通过检查这个key变量
it detects it by checking if this key variable
检测这个key指针是否指向perthread_struct结构
if the key pointer is pointing to the perthread struct
事实证明
right turns out
啊，你们看不到
ah you didn't see that
实际上我们很容易在源码上看出来
actually we can very easily see it on the source
查看malloc.c
so look at malloc.c
然后找一个
and find a
我们来搜索一下
let's search for that
双重释放
double free
哦
oh
奇怪。稍等
that's weird. hold on
浏览器显示不正常
the browser isn't properly
好了
there we go
好吧
alright
让我们复制一下，tcache中的双重释放检测
let's copy double free detected in Tcache
我们可以找到源代码
we can find the source code
好的，稍等
all right hold on
我会回来的
I'll be back
我要找到源代码，把它调出来
I'm gonna find the source code and bring it up
这是malloc的源代码
alright here's the source code for malloc
让我们把它放大一点
let's actually grow it a little bit
好了，这是malloc，它是最新最棒的
alright this is malloc it's the latest and greatest
但是同样的检查也适用于ubuntu 2004
but the same check is in whatever version is in ubuntu 2004
让我们搜索一下双重释放
let's search for double free
查找。在…完美，那个检查就在这里
detect it. in... perfect and here is the check that occurs
它会检查
it literally checks for
e是我们的分配，我们的缓存项
e is our allocation our Tcache entry
然后检查
and then it checks hey
key变量是否等于我们的tcache_perthread_struct
is the key variable equal to our Tcache per thread struct
如果是，它会继续判断确保它是一次正常的释放
if yes it actually goes through and make sure it is a double(口误) allocation
但这个检查
but the check is that
这就是我们要绕过的检查
that's the check we need to defeat
不是双重分配，双重释放
uhh not double allocation double free
如果我们可以写入
so if we have some way to write
一个指向被释放了的内存指针
to the pointer to that allocation after it's freed
正如你前面看到的释放重用一样
and again as you've seen use after free happen
然后我们可以触发双重释放
then we can trigger a double free
看看这个
check this out
我所做的就是破坏了key变量
so all I did was I am corrupting that key variable
把1234填入了内存块的第二个8字节中
the second 8 bytes of my allocation with 1 2 3 4
覆盖了原来的值
instead of the pointer that is there before
如果我运行它
and if I run it
它会，它会释放，它会双重释放
it'll it'll free it'll double free
而且它会通过检查
it'll pass that check
接下来是两个malloc
and then the next two malloc
会返回相同的地址
will return the same address
好的
right
它们只是不停地重复
and they just malloc and malloc
这对一个程序来说是残酷的
that is brutal to a program
这对安全造成了严重影响
it's crippling to security
因为
because again
你最终会得到重叠的分配
you end up with an overlapping allocation
这取决于它们的用途
depending on what those are used for
这可能是非常非常坏的消息
that can be really really bad news
好的，还有一件事
all right what is another thing
哦
oops
另一个问题是Tcache太容易信任别人了
another problem with Tcache being so trusting
好吧
well
Tcache是
Tcache is
很抱歉，Tcache的轻信天性允许我们施展
sorry Tcache's trusting nature allows us to do
一种叫缓存毒化的攻击手段
what is called a cache poisoning attack
基本概念，如果我们破坏缓存entry 的next变量会发生什么
basic idea what happens if we corrupt Tcache entry next
第一个变量
that first variable
作为提示，这个变量指向链表下一部分
as a reminder the variable that points onwards to the next part of the list
当分配时
when it's allocated
当malloc返回一个Tcache_entry时
when a Tcache entry is returned through malloc
它盲目地获取next变量
Tcache blindly takes that next variable
要返回的tcache_entry的next变量
the value of the next pointer of the entry it's about to return
然后把它写在列表的头部
and it puts it into the head of the list
让我们来看看
so let's take a look
会发生什么
what happens
我创建了这个heap_redirection
I created this heap_redirection
如果我们创建一个栈缓冲区
so if we create a stack buffer
或者是我们能控制的其它内存
or another piece of memory that we have we controll
我们释放了很多东西
and we free a bunch of things
来创建一个Tcache链表，来预热
so to create a Tcache link list in memory  to be warm up
这叫做预热tcache
this is called warm up the Tcache
这样做，然后
do this and then
我们利用释放重用
we corrupt using a use after free
来破坏已释放entry的next指针
the next pointer of the freed entry
它原来是指向b, 链表表头
that used to point to b the head of the list
我们最近释放的内存
the last thing that was freed
当我们执行第一个malloc时，它会返回...
when we do our first malloc it'll return oops
当我们执行第一个malloc时，它会返回a
when we do our first malloc it'll return a
当我们做第二个malloc时
when we do our second malloc
它会返回 a 的 next 指向的东西
it'll return what a next was pointing to
就是我们的栈缓冲区
and that is our stack buffer
因为我们用栈地址修改了next指针
because we corrupted that next pointer with our stack buffer
我们可以用任何我们想要的东西来破坏它
we could corrupt it with anything we want
只要是malloc可以返回的有效内存
as long as its valid memory that malloc can return
很酷，这就是
cool so this is
Tcache在总体上是如何运行的
how Tcache works on a high level
还有一些针对它的攻击方法
and some of the attacks that you can yield against it
Tcache基本上是一个针对小内存的缓存层
in summary basically Tcache is a layer for caching small allocations
我记得AMD64上边界值是1036字节
I believe the cut off is 1036 bytes on AMD64
一年前还是两年前是这样的
it was as of a year ago or two years ago
但你可以自己做实验
but you can actually experiment on your own
PWNDBG有一个堆插件
pwndbg has a heap plugin
能让你检查堆的状态
that allows you to examine the state of the heap
你可以看到
and you can actually see
在free和malloc时Tcache的状态
what the state of Tcache is  as you free and malloc and so forth
Tcache使用单链表
Tcache uses a singly linked list
做了很少的安全检查
with very few security checks
这还不是最疯狂的
and this isn't even as insane as it gets
你还能遇到更疯狂的
you're gonna go even crazier
但老实说，在你接下来的挑战问题中
but honestly in your challenge problems and so forth
这差不多是最疯狂的了
this is more or less as insane as it gets
祝你好运
good luck